Beirut, Lebanon

□ (+961) 71-778924 | wissam.antoun@gmail.com | • WissamAntoun | • wissamantoun | • WissamAntoun

Summary _

Current Masters Student at the American University of Beirut, with focus on Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning and specialised in state-of-the-art Natural Language Processing techniques. 2 years of experience in teaching (Graduate Teaching Assistant) in the Electrical Engineering Department. Tech geek who loves computer hardware and technology, and enjoys DIY projects and gaming. Interested in learning new tools and technologies, and in increasing my problem solving skills.

Work Experience _____

Zaka Online

Workshop Instructor May. 2020

Gave a 4-part online workshop series titled A Comprehensive NLP series that was focused on delivering the major NLP concepts through handson coding examples along with the NLP fundamentals theory. Concepts ranged from Bag-of-Words, Word Embeddings, Advanced Deeplearning Models for text, and transformer-based architectures

Stars of Science Doha, Qatai

MACHINE LEARNING EXPERT

Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020

• Provided Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence solutions as part of the support team that helps each contestant throughout their Stars of Science journey

MIND Lab (Prof. Hazem Hajj) - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon Sep. 2018 - Current

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• My research focuses on state-of-the-art NLP technologies for natural language understanding, generation, and social chatbots.

• Worked on pre-training various Arabic language models that ranges from RNN-based to the Transformer-based models, using Cloud TPU and GPU instances.

ECE Dept. - American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2018

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

• EECE 435L: Software Tools Lab, Co-Instructor (3 semesters). Delivered a range of teaching and assessment activities including tutorials directed towards the delivery of modern Software Tools at the undergraduate level. Prepared lab tutorials, graded assignments and provided support for the student projects.

• EECE 696: Applied Parallel Programming, Lab instructor (1 semester). Delivered hands-on experience to graduate students on parallel programming and GPU computing using the CUDA C/C++ framework on local computers and on AWS. Provided office hours, assignment grading and support for course project.

- EECE 330: Data Structures and Algorithms, Lab instructor (1 semester). Delivered hands-on experience on fundamental algorithms and data structures used in software applications at the undergraduate level using C++. Provided weekly assessments, feedback, and support.
- Introduced a plagiarism detection tool for computer code to the Electrical Engineering Department.

Huawei Technologies (Lebanon) S.A.R.L.

Beirut, Lebanon

INTERN

June 2016 - Aug. 2016

• Learned about various LTE principles, base station hardware, and Microwave transmissions systems.

Publications and Presentations

AraBERT: Transformer-based Model for Arabic Language Understanding

Antoun, Wissam, Fady Baly, and Hazem Hajj

Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

Multi-Task Learning using AraBert for Offensive Language Detection

Djandji, Marc, Fady Baly, Wissam Antoun, and Hazem Hajj

Proceedings of the 4th Workshop on Open-Source Arabic Corpora and Processing Tools at LREC 2020, 2020, Marseille, France

State of the Art Models for Fake News Detection Tasks

Antoun, Wissam, Fady Baly, Rim Achour, Amir Hussein, and Hazem Hajj

2020 IEEE International Conference on Informatics, IoT, and Enabling Technologies (ICIoT) (ICIoT'2020), 2020, Doha, Qatar

hULMonA: The Universal Language Model in Arabic

ElJundi, Obeida, **Wissam Antoun**, Nour El Droubi, Hazem Hajj, Wassim El-Hajj, and Khaled Shaban

Proceedings of the Fourth Arabic Natural Language Processing Workshop at ACL, 2019, Florence, Italy

A Comprehensive Approach for A Smart Medication Dispenser

Kassem, Abdallah, **Wissam Antoun**, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary

International Journal of Computing and Digital Systems 8.02 (2019) PP. 131–141. UNIVERSITY OF BAHRAIN, 2019

Smart Medicine Dispenser (SMD)

Antoun, Wissam, Ali Abdo, Suleiman Al-Yaman, Abdallah Kassem, Mustapha Hamad, and Chady El-Moucary 2018 IEEE 4th Middle East Conference on Biomedical Engineering (MECBME), 2018

Real-Time Fire Detection Using CUDA

Antoun, Wissam and Manal Jalloul

ISC High Performance, Poster Presentation, 2019, Frankfurt, Germany

Honors & Awards _____

INTERNATIONAL

2019 **Best Domain Detection system**, Qatar International Fake News Detection and Annotation Contest

Doha, Qatar

DOMESTIC

2019 **Second Place**, Mindsets-OLX Datathon, Best car price prediction score.(www.kaggle.com/c/mindsets)

AUB, Lebanon

2019 **First place**, Big Data, AI, and Media Hackathon Powered by Touch and Anghami

AUB, Lebanon

Presentation

High Performance Computing for Lebanon (HPC4L) Brown Bag

Beirut, Lebanon

PRESENTER FOR CURRENT AND FUTURE/POTENTIAL USE CASES FOR HPC4L

Feb. 2020

- Introduced the use case of HPC for pretraining transformer-based model for Arabic language Understanding
- Explained parallelization and scaling techniques for transformer models

PyData Khobar meetup Onlin

PRESENTER FOR ARABERT: PRETRAINING, USE CASES AND FUTURE IMPROVEMENTS

May. 2012

· Introduced the AraBERT model for the Arab community and explained the pretraining and fine-tuning procedure

Education_

Masters Of Engineering In Electrical And Computer Engineering

Beirut, Lebanon

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT

Feb. 2018 - Current

· Awarded Graduate Fellowship with full tuition coverage

Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer And Communication Engineering

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY - LOUAIZE

Fall. 2014 - Summer 2017

• GPA: 3.58 Dean's List for 6 semesters

CCNA Routing And Switching: Introduction To Networks

Zouk Mosbeh, Lebanon

CISCO NETWORKING ACADEMY- NOTRE DAME UNIVERSITY

Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

Skills

- Proficient in: Python (TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras), NVidia CUDA (Parallel Programming), Matlab, C# and C++.
- Familiar with: Open ComputerVision ,Xilinx, C, VHDL, Java, Qt, SQL.
- Documentation Tools: LaTex, Doxygen, MS-Word.